Jeff Wymore

Software Developer

<u>JeffWymore78@gmail.com</u> <u>https://github.com/yardboy2401</u>

Portfolio

www.linkedin.com/in/jeff-wymore-jw78

425-772-9869 • Wenatchee, WA

Qualifications Summary

Coding bootcamp graduate with extensive experience in several coding languages, developing mobile-first applications, and building websites from the ground up. Specializing in JavaScript, ReactJS, NodeJS, HTML/CSS, MySQL and MongoDB.

Professional strengths include root cause driven problem solving, written and verbal communication, and exceptional time management. Detail-oriented mindset from 15+ years of experience in the tech industry. Skilled technician and engineer with extensive experience in the field. Broad vocational background with various types of equipment. Able to learn concepts quickly and accurately.

- JavaScript
- ReactJS
- NodeJS
- Express JS

- HTML/CSS
- MySQL
- MongoDB
- Bootstrap/Materialize CSS Frameworks

Career Experience

Software Engineering Immersive (Student)

September 2021 - March 2022

Developed several mobile applications and built two user-friendly websites using Full Stack JavaScript/NodeJS/ReactJS and several other programming languages, libraries and frameworks

Noted Projects:

- Created an interactive weather dashboard using 2 separate API calls to display current weather and a 5 day extended forecast for any city searched with the search history stored to browser local storage for easy access. Used HTML, CSS, JavaScript/jQuery.
- Created a collaborative team interactive webpage for searching movie and cocktail recipe data from 3 seaparate API calls with movie search history stored to local storage for easy access and a second HTML page for cocktail recipe information. Used HTML, CSS, JavaScript/jQuery, Materialize CSS framework.
- Created a timed interactive code quiz game using the browser local storage for saving high score with a penalty of timer deduction for missed question(s). Used HTML, CSS, Javascript.

Electronic Service Technician

February 2019 – July 2021

Van Doren Sales

Install and support Compac fruit-sorting equipment at client locations. Setup and configure the computer network, install the solenoid and labeler device, and set up timing. Calibrate the camera and lighting requirements for the equipment to function properly.

Designated as the on-call technician to repair and troubleshoot equipment during cherry season. Maintain and repair Compac equipment. Perform service calls in the Wenatchee area and utilize company truck and equipment to perform assignments.

Knowledgeable and experienced with Durand Wayland (ESOP and Ultra Sort) and Compac (InVision, Sizer, and Spectrim) fruit-sorting software program platforms. Skilled with Sinclair labeling systems in regard to software timing adjustment. Interact with vendors of fruit-sorting manufacturer software systems.

Site Engineer-Seattle

March 2018 to November 2018

Ion Beam Applications (IBA)

Conducted daily proton therapy center protocols, which included start-up procedures, software updates, and testing. Tasked to operate the proton therapy system. Performed duties during high-stress situations caused by system downtime events occurring during clinical patient treatments.

Initiated and promoted continuous client communication concerning the status of the system. Engaged in scheduled maintenance to the patient positioning system, treatment room nozzle components, and the x-ray equipment.

Field Service Engineer

August 2016 - March 2018

Ion Beam Applications (IBA)

Tasked to perform preventative maintenance and repair of proton therapy equipment/systems. Updated cooling and vacuum systems drivers, fiber-optic cables, high and low voltage supply equipment, patient-positioning equipment, PLCs, regulation loops, sensors, and x-ray system. Repaired and calibrated robotics systems.

Traveled throughout the United States to maintain, repair, and upgrade equipment. Participated in arc flash (NFPA 70E) training and learned HIPAA mandates to support the medical environment.

Customer Service Supervisor

June 2011 to August 2016

Sea-Bird Electronics, Inc.

Oversaw the Customer Service group comprised of twelve technicians assigned to support highly-specialized oceanographic equipment. Supplied technical leadership to the technicians who were tasked to maintain and service the entire Sea-Bird product line.

Prepared and participated in 6S/Kaizen/QDIP activities, Utilized LEAN manufacturing management principles.

Education

- University of Washington Software Coding Bootcamp
 24-week intensive software development bootcamp focusing on front end and back end
 technologies, including HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap/Materialize/Tailwind CSS
 frameworks, Express.js, React.js, Node.js, Database Theory, MongoDB, MySQL, Command Line,
 Git, VSCode, GitHub, and much more. Simulated professional work environment by teaming up
 with classmates on real-word projects. Followed model agile environment, based on creating and
- Naval Nuclear Power School
 24-week nuclear and atomic theory, algebra, calculus, chemistry, materials, physics, radiological controls, and thermodynamics.
- Naval Nuclear Field 'A' School

responding to user stories.

- 17-week electrical/electronic, mechanical theory, and motor/generator class, including diagrams, electrical schematics, and mechanical drawings. Topics included calibration, diagnostic test equipment maintenance, and troubleshooting techniques.
- Naval Nuclear Prototype School
 26-week hands-on training, including maintenance and operations on the 450V AC/DC electric plant, operation of the engine room and reactor on the S5W Reactor Plant, and radiological controls.
- Advanced Microsoft Excel
 Two-day seminar to acquire knowledge on charts, macros, pivot tables, and slicers.